sportradar.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy Notice - Sportradar

You are a Third-Party User when you visit a page of a website or application of one of our Sportradar ad:s partners where Sportradar’s or our technology partners’ tags, pixels, other similar technology or content products (widgets) (“ **Sportradar Technology** “) are installed (“ **Partner Sites** “). The Partner Sites belong to online publishers and partners who want to recommend relevant content to their readers or advertisers who want readers to view their content.

For example, our Sportradar Technology is implemented on [LAOLA1.at](https://www.laola1.at/de/). If you click on [LAOLA1.at](https://www.laola1.at/de/)‘s privacy and cookie notices, you will see detailed information that enables you to read this Privacy Notice and our [Cookie Notice](https://www.sportradar.com/about-us/cookies/).

If you would like to know more about the Sportradar ad:s solution, please click here: [https://www.sportradar.com/ads/](https://www.sportradar.com/ads/).

**a. What personal data we collect and Why**

We use online identifiers such as UUIDs, IP address and other usage information so that we can serve interesting content products and recommendations. Sportradar processes your personal data to provide you with the most relevant ads based on your interests. These ads will link a publisher’s website/app to an advertiser’s website/app.

•  Unique User Identifier (UUID)

When as a Third-Party User you first visit a Partner Site (e.g. [LAOLA1.at](https://www.laola1.at/de/)), Sportradar drops a cookie on your device in order to generate an UUID. We catalog and analyze the content you consume across Partner Sites. Our recommendations are based on: (i) your browsing history; (ii) similar browsing patterns of other Third-Party Users; (iii) recommendations that are generally popular with Sportradar’s audience at this time; and (iv) targeting requirements that may be provided or requested by advertisers. As an example, Sportradar may know that UUID 123 (which could be you on your mobile device on [LAOLA1.at](https://www.laola1.at/de/) using Safari as your browser) likes to read sports news about Darts and that people who like to read about Darts will most probably also be interested in sports news about Beach Volleyball.

The UUID is a sequence of numbers and/or letters. This UUID attaches itself to your device and varies depending on which browser you use. In other words, Sportradar records a different UUID depending on which device and/or which browser you use when accessing the Partner Sites. For example, this means that you will have one UUID when you visit a Partner Site from your mobile phone using the browser Safari, and a different UUID when you visit a Partner Site from your iPad using the browser Safari. Sportradar will combine and consolidate a UUID from a mobile device (phone or tablet) from a browser that then accesses an application (or vice versa) from that same device.

Assigning an UUID allows Sportradar to associate the page views and clicks on Sportradar’s delivered ads from such UUID – all with the goal of providing interesting recommendations.

Apart from UUID, we also collect the following information from you:

• the internet protocol (IP) address of the device you are using  
• cookie ID and other online user identifier(s)  
• your device type (e.g. iPhone), your browser type (e.g. Chrome), your operating system (e.g. iOS), your screen resolution  
• the language your browser is set to and/or used for our interactive features and respective contents on our Partner Sites  
• the date and time of access of our Partner Sites  
• your mouse movements, clicks and location  
• referring URLs and other information normally transmitted in HTTP requests (e.g. this information tells us where you arrived on our Partner Sites from)  
• location data (country and region)  
• information on how you use our Partner Sites (e.g. the web pages visited by you on our Partner Sites) and how you interact with our interactive features and respective contents on our Partner Sites.

The above information provides us with insights about how many Third-Party Users have visited a specific page on our Partner Sites on which the Sportradar Technology is present, how long each User stayed on that page, the type of content on that page they clicked on and how they generally engaged with that page. This information is only personal data when it is associated with a UUID.

**b. What cookies and other similar technologies we use**

Please see our [Cookie Notice](https://www.sportradar.com/about-us/cookies/) under “Third-Party Users” for a detailed list of cookies we use when you interact with Partner Sites where the Sportradar Technology is implemented.

If, for example, you load a webpage containing recommendations, the advertisers sponsoring the recommendations may place cookies on your device through redirects prior to arriving on the destination page of the recommendations or upon reaching the destination page. In such cases you will be subject to the advertisers’ privacy policies.

Sportradar advertisers implement the Sportradar pixel on their websites. Sportradar determines whether the user reaching the page where the pixel is installed has a Sportradar UUID. Sportradar further implements cookie sync with advertisers in order to be able to run retargeting advertising campaigns.

Data points such as page views and clicks that are connected to a particular UUID are retained for **18 months**. For example, if UUID 123 views a particular webpage on 31 December, 2017, on 1 September 2019 that information (i.e. the webpage view event) will no longer be part of UUID 123’s profile.

**c. How we may share information**

Sportradar does not share user segments with any third parties. However, we may share the UUID and other usage information with certain partners for the purpose of cookie syncing, or based on technical requirements.

**Recipients of Personal Data (Controllers)**

Advertising partners we currently work (or will shortly be working) with are:

**_•   Google LLC_**

**Service:**  Google Ad Manager is an advertising service provided by Google LLC that allows us to run advertising campaigns in conjunction with external advertising networks. In order to get more information about Google’s use of data, please read [How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/) or consult [Google’s privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-US). Google LLC is a Privacy Shield participant.

**Personal Data Processed** : Online identifiers such as cookies and web beacons (including IP address).

**Location:**  1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA

**_•   The Rubicon Project Inc._**

**Service:**  The Rubicon Project is a real-time advertising technology platform provider which facilitates transactions between publishers and buyers and ad serving. In order to get more information about Rubicon’s use of data, please consult [Rubicon Project Advertising Technology Privacy Policy](https://rubiconproject.com/rubicon-project-advertising-technology-privacy-policy/). Should you wish to opt out of the use of information about the websites you visit in order to deliver targeted advertising to you, you can do so using the opt-out tool on the Rubicon Project’ website, at [http://rubiconproject.com/privacy/consumer-online-profile-and-opt-out/](http://rubiconproject.com/privacy/consumer-online-profile-and-opt-out/).

**Personal Data Processed** : Online identifiers such as cookie and device related identifiers.

**Location:**  12181 Bluff Creek Drive, Playa Vista, CA 90094 USA

Additionally, you can opt out from being tracked by various advertising networks by using Your Online Choices ([http://www.youronlinechoices.com/](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/)).

For more information, please see also  **Section 9 (How We Share Your Personal Data)**  of this Privacy Notice.

**d. Your rights**

For more information, please see also **Section 11 (What Data Protection Rights You Have)** of this Privacy Notice.

**e. Lawful Basis for Processing**

Sportradar’s lawful basis for processing a Third-Party User’s personal data is based on the lawful basis determined by each of our Partner Sites. Each Partner Site will rely on _**consent**_ or _**legitimate interest**_. Please consult the applicable Partner Sites’ privacy policies for more information about their lawful basis. If a Partner is relying on consent, Sportradar will not drop a cookie on you if you have not provided consent on such Partner Site.

Back to top
